<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin McGregor</title>
    <link>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kevin McGregor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trainees</title>
      <link>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/trainees/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/trainees/</guid>
      <description>I am supervising two undergraduate research assistants for the summer of 2021
 Yutong Chen (YorkU Dean&amp;rsquo;s Undergraduate Research Award recipient) Nneka Okaeme  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Kevin</title>
      <link>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an Assistant Professor in York University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Mathematics and Statistics.
My research interests include:
 Microbiome data analysis Statistical genetics Analysis of high-dimensional data Network analysis in microbiome data Bayesian statistical methods Statistical analysis of DNA methylation data  I did my PhD at McGill University in the Department of Epidemiology, Biostatistics, and Occupational Health. My co-supervisors were Celia Greenwood and Aurélie Labbe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description> MDiNE (Microbiome Differential Network Estimation)
 Bayesian model to estimate precision matrix based network changes with respect to a binary covariate.  MiCoRe (Microbiome Covariance Regresion)
 Bayesian model to estimate covariance matrix changes with respect to a covariate profile in microbiome data.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining York University</title>
      <link>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/posts/joining_york/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/posts/joining_york/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to announce that, in January 2021, I will be joining York University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Mathematics and Statistics at the rank of Assistant Professor! Go Lions!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Published Articles  Kevin McGregor, Aurélie Labbe, Celia MT Greenwood. Microbiome co-occurrence network estimation using covariance regression. Submitted to Biometrics in June 2020
 McGregor, Kevin, Aurélie Labbe, and Celia MT Greenwood. &amp;ldquo;MDiNE: a model to estimate differential co-occurrence networks in microbiome studies.&amp;rdquo; Bioinformatics 36.6 (2020): 1840-1847.
 Lea Thaler, Sarah Brassard, Esther Kahan, Kevin McGregor, Aurelie Labbe, Mimi Israel, and Howard Steiger. Methylation of the OXTR gene in women with Anorexia Nervosa: Relationship to Social Behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeding out the competition</title>
      <link>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/posts/weed_competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/posts/weed_competition/</guid>
      <description>I may be a little late to the game on this one, but a few months ago there was some controversy surrounding Saskatchewan&amp;rsquo;s cannabis licensing lottery, where several businesses won multiple permits across the province despite a large number of applicants in each municipality. One cannabis company, Prairie Sky Cannabis, was able to obtain four permits: one in each of Battleford, Estevan, Martensville and Moosomin. An article in the Leader Post claimed the probability of this happening was only 1 in 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post on new site</title>
      <link>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/posts/first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/posts/first_post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my personal website! This is my very first post&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m still getting used to the paricularities of using Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Kevin</title>
      <link>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/kindex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/kindex/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently a PhD candidate in Biostatistics in McGill University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Epidemiology, Biostatistics, and Occupational Health. My co-supervisors are Celia Greenwood and Aurélie Labbe.
My research interests include:
 Statistical genetics Analysis of high-dimensional data Network analysis in microbiome data Bayesian statistical methods Statistical analysis of DNA methylation data  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevinmcgregor.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Course instructor  MATH 2930 - Introductory Probability and Statistics
 York University, Fall 2021  MATH 4931 - Simulation and the Monte Carlo Method
 York University, Winter 2021, Winter 2022  MATH 6635 - Introduction to Bayesian Statistics
 York University, Winter 2022  EPIB 521 - Regression Analysis for Health Sciences
 McGill University, Winter 2018  Lady Davis Institute Seminar Series in Biostatistics
 Lady Davis Institute for Medical Research - Fall 2017 (Lecture notes)   Teaching assistant  EDPE 676 - Intermediate Statistics</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>